# Dhanush Saji

## Full Stack Developer



- dhanushsaji1@gmail.com
- **\$547074716**
- Pathanamthitta, Kerala, India
- **1** 06/03/1998
- in dhanush-saji
- Ohanush-Saji
- Dhanush-Saji

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An enthusiastic Full Stack Developer with hands-on experience in website development using the MERN stack and many web technologies such as HTML, CSS, and JS. I'm excited to contribute significantly to the team's success through hard effort, attention to detail, and good organisational abilities.

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

**UI/UX Designer,** Byte Infotech 01/2021 - 01/2022 | Trivandrum, India

- Worked on a project for the Telangana government
- Designed UI with Figma, Adobe XD, leveraging associated models and tools to reduce development time

## Freelance Graphic designer

08/2020 - 12/2020

## Interests

Guitarist | Singer

#### **Awards**

#### **Certificate of Achievement**

2020

Awarded a Certificate of Achievement for developing the project 'KTU Guru'

#### **SKILLS**

### **Technical Skills**

ReactJs | Node.Js | JavaScript | HTML | CSS | TailwindCSS | MongoDB | Mongoose | Chakra-UI | GitHub | Open AI | Git | DSA | ExpressJs | Material-UI | Postman | Figma | Bootstrap | C |

#### **Soft Skills**

Teamwork | Problem Solving | Remote Work | Proactive | Time Management | Self-learning

#### **PROJECTS**

## White Feather ∂ ( )



White Feather is a women cosmetic e-commerce platform.

## Tech - Stack used: ReactJS, Chakra UI

## Area of responsibility:

- Login (authentication)
- Navbar

A collaborative project was developed within 5 days with a team of 5 people.

## Semrush Clone ⊘ ( )



Semrush is a website which offer SEO services, SMM, Content marketing, etc

## Tech-Stack used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

#### Area of responsibility:

- Feature page
- Blog page

An individual project was developed within 5 days.

## The Little Al ⊘



The Little AI is a website which includes a chatbot that comprehends human speech nuances, responds contextually

## Tech - Stack used: ReactJS, Chakra UI, Open AI

## Area of responsibility:

- Login (authentication)
- Landing page
- Chat Page

An individual project was developed within 4 days.

### **EDUCATION**

## Full Stack Web Development (Full-time), Masai School

05/2022 - 02/2023

**Btech in Computer Science,** College of Engineering, Muttathara,

07/2016 - 05/2020 | Trivandrum

### Higher Secondary Education, S.V.G.V.H.S.S

06/2014 - 03/2016 | Pathanamthitta

#### **Activities**

#### KTU Guru ∂

An E-Learning website for Kerala Technical University students

Tech-Stack used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP

Developed an E-learning platform for students under KTU(Kerala Technological University)

#### Area of responsibility:

- UI/UX Designing
- Graphic Designing

A collaborative project developed within 3 months, with a team of 9.